<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Emails - Math345 - Autumn 2010</title>
<link>http://www.math.osu.edu/~fowler/teaching/</link>
<atom:link href="http://www.math.osu.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/email-index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<description>
Emails from the Autumn 2010 quarter of Math345, taught by Jim Fowler.
</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2010 Jim Fowler</copyright>
<managingEditor>fowler@math.osu.edu (Jim Fowler)</managingEditor>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 14:19:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>60</ttl>


<item>
<title>[Math345] The first homework set.</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have posted the first homework set at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/homework01.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you have trouble with the homework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My video system didn&apos;t quite work today, but I&apos;ll try again Thursday, so hopefully tomorrow&apos;s lecture will have better video.  Here&apos;s what happened today:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/video/lecture01.mov&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you have trouble viewing the video, or if you have other thoughts on this so-called video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;thank you, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 20:15:14 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] The Upcoming Midterm</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, October 19, instead of lecture, we will take the first midterm for Math 345.  To help you to prepare, I have written a review sheet listing the topics you should be expecting:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/midterm1-review.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have also produced a &quot;fake midterm&quot; and posted it at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/fake-midterm1.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fake midterm has the same style of question as the real midterm will have, but the fake midterm is much, much longer.  The real midterm will have five questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will have a chance to talk during lecture on Monday about the midterm, but if you have questions before then, please don&apos;t hesitate to email me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;wishing you all the best, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 12:07:26 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] Review session.</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There will be a review for next week&apos;s final exam: the review session will be Friday, December 3 from 9:40am until 11:30am, in CH240 (which, confusingly, is the same as MA240, but it is a lovely room, so we&apos;re lucky to be able to reserve it).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CH240 is between Cockins Hall and the Math Building, so you can get to Room 240 from either building.  Also, I will be in my office from 3:00pm until 4:30pm on Friday, December 3, so we can talk then if the review session doesn&apos;t work for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We still have class tomorrow (Thursday, December 2).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And finally, if you have a chance, please submit an SEI for Math 345; your evaluations are very important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; please let me know if you have questions, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 1 Dec 2010 8:10:05 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] Posted homework.</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As pointed out today in lecture, the website was missing the most recent homework assignments!  I&apos;ve posted the new assignments at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;and the homework should also appear on Carmen soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; thanks, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 16:31:27 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] Office Hours, repeating decimals</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow (Wednesday, October 13), I will be substitute teaching in a calculus class from 1:30 until 2:30pm, which obliterates my office hours.  So I will hold office hours tomorrow from 3:30 until 4:30pm instead.  In any case, if you can&apos;t make it to my regular office hours but want to talk, please email me and we can find a different time to meet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And if you&apos;re ever confused about the homework, please email me; I&apos;m also happy to help you with homework remotely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for submitting responses to the survey from last week; about 80% of you said that you liked having homework every day instead of every week, so we will keep with this schedule.  The survey also suggests that you are mostly happy with the pace and content, but if you would like the course to move faster or slower, or in a different direction, let me know.  Once we introduce induction (right after the midterm), we will have some flexibility as to the topics we can cover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of midterms: there is a midterm in one week!  Soon I will post a fake midterm and review materials on the website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to a question in lecture, I&apos;ve posted a handout&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.osu.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/point-nine-repeating.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;discussing very briefly why 0.99999... is actually another name for 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;thanks, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 12:07:26 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] End of week two.</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had a discussion today in the second lecture today about Goedel&apos;s incompleteness theorems and geometry; there&apos;s an article on Wikipedia about this at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Godel&apos;s_incompleteness_theorems&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did not know this, but there is an axiomatization (due to Tarski) of a large piece of Euclidean geometry, which has been shown to be complete, consistent, and even decideable.  You can read about this at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tarski&apos;s_axioms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a way of encoding geometric facts in symbols, using the relationships of &quot;between&quot; and &quot;congruent.&quot;  One of the nicest things about teaching is getting to learn new things, so I&apos;m grateful for finding out about this today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Videos of the lectures are now available on &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The quality will keep getting better as I figure out how to handle the video.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The homework, although graded out of 18 points, will be counted out of 60 points; so your scores will be rescaled to adjust for this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;thank you for a great week, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 19:32:26 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] Week one, done.</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s a new survey available at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  https://spreadsheets.google.com/viewform?formkey=dEczTkE2RHk5NDNTT0hSa0hOc0EwRVE6MQ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have posted the second homework set at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/homework02.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to email me if you have trouble completing the homework, or if there are other things you want to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can view a &quot;video&quot; of the second lecture at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/video/lecture02.flv&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;or if that doesn&apos;t work, try&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/video/lecture02.mov&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; looking forward to collecting your homework on Monday, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 20:38:30 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] Survey, tutoring, videos, note-taking</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, there&apos;s a new survey available at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  https://spreadsheets.google.com/viewform?formkey=dHJBaXhrYUV6aWh6SHV0NmNxSHRsNkE6MQ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I appreciate your taking the time to provide any feedback as to how I can make your Math 345 experience better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second, if you are looking for additional tutoring, there are new tutorial hours for Math 345 in the MSLC; there is more about this at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.mslc.ohio-state.edu/about/location/345&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Third, there are videos of the lectures posted at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;but the videos are usually a couple of days behind (it takes media services a little while to prepare the videos for streaming).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fourth and very importantly, there is a student in the class who is looking for a note-taking assistant; if you could copy your notes for this student, please write to me and I can help you arrange this.  You will be paid $10 per credit hour at the end of the quarter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; have a great weekend, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 16:51:46 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


<item>
<title>[Math345] The Last Week</title>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear Math345er,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s arrived: the final week of the quarter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SEIs: If you have a chance, please go to your class schedule and click the Evaluation button next to Math 345.  Your taking the time to submit an evaluation means a lot to me personally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peer review: Earlier today, I sent you an email with a PDF attached; your comments on your fellow students&apos; homework are worth 370 points. The due date is before the final exam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Short paper: For 360 points, you can submit a short paper on a topic in mathematics.  This is due before the final exam.  More instructions are available at:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/short-paper-instructions.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final exam: next week is our final exam!  There is a review sheet available at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/final-review.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;and a fake final available at&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  http://www.math.ohio-state.edu/~fowler/teaching/math345/fake-final.pdf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will hold a review session on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; let me know if you have questions, ~jim &lt;/p&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 20:10:05 -0400</pubDate>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>
